Subtitle Provide by dramacool.asia Translator [Admin.@YNG]
تم توفير الترجمة بواسطة مترجم dramacool.asia [Admin.@YNG]
[Echoes of the Self]
[أصداء الذات]
Mrs. Zhou,
السيدة تشو،
this tea is what I've granted to you.
هذا الشاي هو ما منحته لك.
you must drink it.
يجب عليك شربه.
I really
انا حقا
cannot drink it.
لا أستطيع شربه.
Why are you so resistant, Mrs. Zhou?
لماذا أنت مقاومة هكذا، السيدة تشو؟
Could there be something wrong with this tea?
هل يمكن أن يكون هناك خطأ في هذا الشاي؟
This does not make sense.
هذا لا معنى له.
If there is something wrong with this tea,
إذا كان هناك خطأ في هذا الشاي،
how would you know about it, Mrs. Zhou?
كيف عرفتِ ذلك يا سيدتي تشو؟
No...
لا...
There's nothing wrong with it.
لا يوجد شيء خاطئ في ذلك.
How could there be?
كيف يمكن أن يكون هناك؟
Is there really nothing wrong with it?
هل هناك حقا أي خطأ في ذلك؟
Would it cause something like
هل سيؤدي ذلك إلى حدوث شيء مثل
tuberculosis,
مرض الدرن،
which might make a person bedridden?
ما الذي قد يجعل الشخص طريح الفراش؟
The poisoning symptoms
أعراض التسمم
are like those of tuberculosis.
مثل تلك الموجودة في مرض السل.
In mild cases,
في الحالات الخفيفة،
a person may become bedridden.
قد يصبح الشخص طريح الفراش.
This person
هذا الشخص
may even die.
وقد يموت حتى.
In severe cases,
في الحالات الشديدة،
a person may even die.
وقد يموت الشخص أيضًا.
Madam.
سيدتي.
Mrs. Zhou.
السيدة تشو.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
This tea
هذا الشاي
is peach kernel tea I brought from Daqing.
شاي نواة الخوخ هو الذي أحضرته من داتشينغ.
It's not the deadly poison
إنه ليس السم القاتل
delivered by Xi.
ألقاها شي.
However, let me give you some advice, too.
ولكن دعني أقدم لك بعض النصائح أيضًا.
From now on,
من الآن فصاعدا،
I'm the protector of Xi and her mother.
أنا حامي شي ووالدتها.
Even after I get married,
حتى بعد أن تزوجت،
I will never abandon them.
لن أتخلى عنهم أبدًا.
So,
لذا،
cease your
توقف عن
malicious intentions and dirty tricks.
النوايا الخبيثة والخدع القذرة.
Otherwise,
خلاف ذلك،
I will make you pay the price.
سأجعلك تدفع الثمن.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
It's alright now, Madam.
كل شيء على ما يرام الآن، سيدتي.
[Prince Yan's Mansion]
[قصر الأمير يان]
Only by completely solving the loan sharking case
فقط من خلال حل قضية القروض الربوية بشكل كامل
can I truly protect Mother and Xi.
هل يمكنني حقًا حماية أمي و شي؟
The only person I can trust now
الشخص الوحيد الذي أستطيع أن أثق به الآن
[Prince Yan's Mansion]
[قصر الأمير يان]
is Yan.
هو يان.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
why are you here?
لماذا انت هنا؟
Lieutenant Liang.
الملازم ليانغ.
Liang Feng!
ليانغ فنغ!
How have you been lately?
كيف حالك في الآونة الأخيرة؟
I...
أنا...
I've been fine.
لقد كنت بخير.
Take me to see Prince Yan.
خذني لرؤية الأمير يان.
Your Highness, please come in.
صاحب السمو، من فضلك ادخل.
[Prince Yan's Mansion]
[قصر الأمير يان]
Your Highness, are you trying to say that
صاحب السمو هل تحاول أن تقول ذلك؟
my carefully selected future husband...
زوجي المستقبلي الذي اخترته بعناية...
is you?
هل انت؟
Princess Fu Wei.
الأميرة فو وي.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
the princess is here.
الأميرة هنا.
Please.
لو سمحت.
What brings you
ما الذي يجلب لك
here today?
هنا اليوم؟
Prince Yan,
الأمير يان
regarding the posthouse incident,
بخصوص حادثة مكتب البريد،
I wonder
انا اتعجب
whether there's any progress.
هل هناك أي تقدم؟
Princess,
أميرة،
do you recognize this?
هل تعرف هذا؟
This was taken from the corpses of
تم أخذ هذا من جثث
Daqing's Peace-Making Marriage Delegation after they were assassinated
وفد زواج داتشينغ للسلام بعد اغتيالهم
in the posthouse.
في مكتب البريد.
It's a black iron dart from Daqing Wolf Camp.
إنه سهم حديدي أسود من معسكر ذئب داتشينغ.
Are you suspecting that
هل تشك في ذلك؟
I demand to arrest the culprit when I'm actually the mastermind?
أطالب بإلقاء القبض على الجاني بينما أنا في الواقع العقل المدبر؟
Your safety concerns diplomatic relations between our two countries.
سلامتكم تهم العلاقات الدبلوماسية بين بلدينا.
However, someone
ومع ذلك، شخص ما
dared to commit an assassination
تجرأ على ارتكاب جريمة اغتيال
in the Imperial City's posthouse.
في مكتب بريد المدينة الإمبراطورية.
I guess
اعتقد
no matter who this person is,
بغض النظر عن من هو هذا الشخص،
his purpose
هدفه
is to provoke conflicts between Yunrui and Daqing.
هو إثارة الصراعات بين يونروي وداتشينغ.
Fighting at wars
القتال في الحروب
requires money.
يتطلب المال.
What do you mean?
ماذا تقصد؟
Yunrui's loan sharking problem
مشكلة تقاسم قروض Yunrui
has been rampant lately.
وقد انتشر على نطاق واسع في الآونة الأخيرة.
Even the women of Zhou's Mansion
حتى نساء قصر تشو
and their maternal families are involved.
وعائلاتهم الأمومية متورطة.
I guess there's a hidden connection among them.
أعتقد أن هناك علاقة خفية بينهم.
I want you to help me verify it.
أريد منك أن تساعدني في التحقق من ذلك.
You're so concerned about this matter.
أنت قلق جدًا بشأن هذه المسألة.
I assume
انا افترض
it's for your aunt, huh?
إنها لعمتك، أليس كذلك؟
You're so insightful.
أنت ثاقب جدًا.
But you're not quite close to your aunt.
ولكنك لست قريبًا تمامًا من عمتك.
Why are you helping her to such an extent?
لماذا تساعدها إلى هذا الحد؟
Though my aunt and I aren't close,
على الرغم من أنني وخالتي لسنا قريبين،
she's still related to me by blood.
لا تزال مرتبطة بي بالدم.
Besides,
بجانب،
I also can't stand seeing people being bullied.
أنا أيضا لا أستطيع أن أتحمل رؤية الناس يتعرضون للتنمر.
But what makes you think that
ولكن ما الذي يجعلك تعتقد ذلك؟
I'll definitely help you?
سأساعدك بالتأكيد؟
Because you're soft-hearted
لأنك طيب القلب
and can't bear to see the weak people being bullied.
ولا أستطيع أن أتحمل رؤية الضعفاء يتعرضون للتنمر.
I'm...
أنا أكون...
soft-hearted?
طيب القلب؟
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Go investigate
اذهب للتحقيق
the clues related to the loan sharking case.
الأدلة المتعلقة بقضية القروض الربوية.
[Victim List of the Loan Sharking Case]
[قائمة ضحايا قضية القروض الربوية]
Yes, sir.
نعم سيدي.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
The posthouse case hasn't been solved yet.
قضية البريد لم يتم حلها بعد
Why do you suddenly want to investigate the loan sharking case?
لماذا تريد فجأة التحقيق في قضية القروض الربوية؟
Do you
هل أنت
really believe in what Princess Fu Wei said?
هل تؤمن حقًا بما قالته الأميرة فو وي؟
In my opinion,
في رأيي،
this princess isn't as simple as she seems.
هذه الأميرة ليست بسيطة كما تبدو.
Your Highness, don't fall into her badger-game trap.
صاحب السمو، لا تقع في فخها.
Who are you exactly?
من أنت بالضبط؟
Why do you always appear in my dreams?
لماذا تظهر دائما في أحلامي؟
[Zhou's Mansion]
[قصر تشو]
Xi.
شي.
Mother.
الأم.
These days,
في هذه الأيام،
you've lost weight again.
لقد فقدت وزنك مرة أخرى.
In the future,
في المستقبل،
if I pass away,
إذا توفيت
how will you
كيف سوف تفعل ذلك
manage on your own?
إدارة نفسك؟
That won't happen.
هذا لن يحدث .
You'll be fine.
سوف تكون بخير.
Mother.
الأم.
Silly child.
طفل سخيف.
Separation in life and death
الانفصال في الحياة والموت
is quite common.
أمر شائع جدًا.
Remember this.
تذكر هذا.
After I pass away,
بعد وفاتي،
you can only cry for a few days.
لا يمكنك البكاء إلا لبضعة أيام.
After that,
بعد ذلك،
dry your tears
جفف دموعك
and live well.
وعيش حياة جيدة.
My only regret is that
ندمي الوحيد هو أن
I cannot stay with my Xi
لا أستطيع البقاء مع شي
for a little longer.
لفترة أطول قليلا.
I don't expect
لا اتوقع
you can have great wealth or a high status.
من الممكن أن يكون لديك ثروة كبيرة أو مكانة عالية.
I only hope
انا فقط اتمنى
you can stay healthy
يمكنك البقاء بصحة جيدة
and safe year after year.
وآمنة سنة بعد سنة.
I will.
أنا سوف.
I definitely will.
بالتأكيد سأفعل.
Remember
يتذكر
to keep
للحفاظ على
this jade pendant well.
هذه القلادة اليشمية جيدة.
At a critical moment,
في لحظة حرجة،
maybe
ربما
it can save your life.
يمكن أن ينقذ حياتك.
Mother.
الأم.
This is...
هذا هو...
Mother!
الأم!
Mother.
الأم.
Xi.
شي.
Mother!
الأم!
How could this happen?
كيف يمكن أن يحدث هذا؟
Why are this happening?
لماذا يحدث هذا؟
Mother!
الأم!
My Lord!
سيدي!
I'm innocent!
أنا بريء!
Mother!
الأم!
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Your Highness, you're finally awake.
صاحب السمو، لقد استيقظت أخيرا.
You've been unconscious for so long.
لقد كنت فاقدًا للوعي لفترة طويلة.
Where is Madam Wang?
أين السيدة وانغ؟
How is she?
كيف حالها؟
Madam Wang...
السيدة وانغ...
Madam Wang has passed away.
لقد توفيت السيدة وانغ.
Your Highness!
صاحب السمو!
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
How could this happen?
كيف يمكن أن يحدث هذا؟
It was that bowl of medicine.
لقد كان ذلك وعاء الدواء.
Someone must have put poison in that bowl of medicine.
لا بد أن يكون أحدهم قد وضع السم في وعاء الدواء.
Lord Zhou has already sent people to investigate it.
وقد أرسل اللورد تشو أشخاصًا للتحقيق في الأمر بالفعل.
They said there was nothing wrong with the medicine.
قالوا أنه لا يوجد شيء خاطئ في الدواء.
The doctor said
قال الطبيب
Madam Wang had been ill from years of overwork,
كانت السيدة وانج مريضة بسبب سنوات من العمل الشاق،
and after being flogged,
وبعد أن جُلِد،
she failed to survive.
فشلت في البقاء على قيد الحياة.
Your Highness!
صاحب السمو!
This substitute not only resembles Miss Zhou Ruoxi,
هذا البديل لا يشبه الآنسة تشو روكسي فحسب،
but she's also heartbroken about Madam Wang's death.
لكنها أيضًا حزينة بشأن وفاة السيدة وانج.
Why is that?
لماذا هذا؟
Why?
لماذا؟
Why was the ending still the same
لماذا كانت النهاية كما هي؟
after I came back to this life?
بعد أن عدت إلى هذه الحياة؟
I couldn't save
لم أستطع الحفظ
those who I wanted to save.
الذين أردت إنقاذهم.
I couldn't keep
لم أستطع الاستمرار
those who I wanted to keep.
الذين أردت الاحتفاظ بهم.
Why did Heaven let me come back?
لماذا سمحت لي السماء بالعودة؟
This is just a joke.
هذه مجرد مزحة.
A joke.
نكتة.
Princess,
أميرة،
you're drunk.
أنت في حالة سكر.
Since you're here,
بما أنك هنا،
why don't you have a drink with me?
لماذا لا تشرب معي؟
Let me tell you a story.
دعني أخبرك بقصة.
Once upon a time,
كان ياما كان،
there was a person who was alone and helpless.
كان هناك شخص وحيد وعاجز.
Even her closest one was killed, too.
حتى أقرب شخص لها قُتل أيضًا.
She wanted to take revenge,
أرادت الانتقام
but she didn't have such ability.
لكنها لم تكن تمتلك مثل هذه القدرة.
She could only take advantage of others.
لم يكن بإمكانها سوى الاستفادة من الآخرين.
She thought after she gained a high status,
فكرت بعد أن حصلت على مكانة عالية،
everything would be different.
كل شيء سيكون مختلفا.
But in the end, she still caused her own death.
ولكن في النهاية، كانت هي السبب في موتها.
She also caused the death of the only person who cared about her.
كما أنها تسببت في موت الشخص الوحيد الذي كان يهتم بها.
She was not willing to accept this ending.
لم تكن مستعدة لقبول هذه النهاية.
Fortunately, Heaven pitied her
لحسن الحظ، أشفقت عليها السماء.
and gave her a chance to start over.
وأعطتها فرصة للبدء من جديد.
But she still messed things up.
لكنها لا تزال تفسد الأمور.
She was so useless.
لقد كانت عديمة الفائدة تماما.
Nothing was changed in the end.
ولم يتغير شيء في النهاية.
No.
لا.
It was worse than before.
لقد كان أسوأ من ذي قبل.
It was more tragic than before.
لقد كان الأمر أكثر مأساوية من ذي قبل.
It was...
لقد كان...
Princess.
أميرة.
Gains, losses, glory and failure are all determined by Heaven.
المكاسب والخسائر والمجد والفشل كلها تحددها السماء.
What we can do as humans
ما يمكننا فعله كبشر
is to do our best and strive for what we want.
هو أن نبذل قصارى جهدنا ونسعى جاهدين لتحقيق ما نريد.
I believe
انا أؤمن
you're not someone who would give up easily.
أنت لست شخصًا يستسلم بسهولة.
Isn't that right?
أليس هذا صحيحا؟
Yes, that's right.
نعم هذا صحيح.
I shouldn't give up so easily.
لا ينبغي لي أن أستسلم بسهولة.
[Zhou's Mansion]
[قصر تشو]
Mother!
الأم!
Wait!
انتظر!
Go away!
يبتعد!
I beg you!
أرجوك!
This will never end, huh?
هذا لن ينتهي أبدًا، أليس كذلك؟
-Go away! -Wait!
-اذهب بعيدا! -انتظر!
Mother!
الأم!
Step aside!
تنحى!
Father!
أب!
Big Mother!
الأم الكبيرة!
I beg you.
أرجوك.
Please let my mother's memorial tablet be placed in the ancestral hall.
أرجو أن يتم وضع لوحة والدتي التذكارية في القاعة الأجدادية.
Can you?
هل تستطيع؟
She doesn't deserve it.
إنها لا تستحق ذلك.
Nor do you!
ولا انت!
Give it to me.
أعطيني إياه.
Dream on!
إحلم!
Xi.
شي.
Xi, stand up first.
شي، قف أولاً.
Whatever it is,
مهما كان الأمر،
discuss it properly with Father.
ناقش الأمر بشكل صحيح مع الأب.
You worthless woman!
يا امرأة لا قيمة لك!
In Zhou's Mansion,
في قصر تشو،
how dare you, a concubine's daughter, act so impudently?
كيف تجرؤين يا ابنة المحظية على التصرف بوقاحة كهذه؟
Father, you married my mother back then
أبي، لقد تزوجت أمي في ذلك الوقت
to take advantage of the Wang family's influence.
للاستفادة من نفوذ عائلة وانغ.
Later, the Wang family fell.
وفي وقت لاحق، سقطت عائلة وانغ.
Then you married another woman.
ثم تزوجت امرأة أخرى.
Xi.
شي.
Stop talking about it.
توقف عن الحديث عن هذا الأمر.
You formed a connection‌ with the Cui family.
لقد شكلت علاقة؟؟؟ مع عائلة كوي.
And now you want to use
والآن تريد استخدام
my eldest sister's friendship with the Crown Prince
صداقة أختي الكبرى مع ولي العهد
to let him marry your daughter and form a connection with him.
لتسمحي له بالزواج من ابنتك وتكوين علاقة معه.
You...
أنت...
Father, you've made such an elaborate plan
يا أبي، لقد وضعت خطة مفصلة للغاية
and have been so visionary‌.
ولقد كانت رؤية واضحة جدًا؟؟؟
Yet can't you tolerate a small memorial tablet?
ولكن هل لا تستطيع أن تتسامح مع لوحة تذكارية صغيرة؟
You...
أنت...
I...
أنا...
It looks like you weren't slapped hard enough.
يبدو أنك لم تتلق صفعة قوية بما فيه الكفاية.
How dare you openly defy your father?
كيف تجرؤ على تحدي والدك علانية؟
Guards!
حراس!
Here!
هنا!
Beat her severely!
اضربها بشدة!
Yes!
نعم!
Mother.
الأم.
What are you waiting for?
ماذا تنتظر؟
Your mother
والدتك
can never enter the ancestral hall of Zhou's Mansion.
لا يمكن أبدًا دخول قاعة أسلاف قصر تشو.
Who says my aunt wants to enter the ancestral hall of Zhou's Mansion?
من قال أن عمتي تريد دخول قاعة الأجداد في قصر تشو؟
[Deep Roots; Lush Branches]
[جذور عميقة؛ فروع خصبة]